Guide to the Albert Galloway Keller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Memorabilia, 1885-1957; Series VI; 1 linear feet (3 boxes)
  - Tributes to Keller
    - Speeches honoring Keller at his testimonial dinner, 1942 January 17 (Box 56, Folder 1467)
    - Keller dinner: eulogy of Albert Keller by Carl Keller, 1942 (Box 56, Folder 1468)
    - certificates, 1942 (Box 56, Folder 1468)
    - Press releases on the death of Keller, 1956 October (Box 56, Folder 1469)
    - Comment and obituaries on Keller by Maurice R. Davie, 1956-1957 (Box 56, Folder 1469)
- Additional material, 1888-1947; Accession 1989-M-015; 0.5; (1 box)
  Addition Inventory by Carol King 1988 October
  Received from: Watkinson Library, Trinity College, 1988 Jul 1
  - Correspondence
    - Allen, Philip R., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Andrews, Edward H., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Angell, James R., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Atterbury, Albert H., 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Babb, James T., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bayne, Hugh A., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bennitt, Chandler, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - [Bridgman?], Walter R., undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Browning, Philip R., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Daus, E.S., 1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Davidson, Eugene, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Day, [Clarence?], 1908, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Day, George Parmly, 1910-1911, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dickey, W. Laurence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Donaldson, Norman V., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dorfman, Joseph, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Doring, J.F., 1932, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Drake, Herbert A., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Farnam, Henry W., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fisher, Irving, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fleming, James E., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Foote, Arthur E., 1940, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ford, Washington C., 1892 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Freidel, Frank, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Glazier, Charles M., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Godfrey, Kenneth, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Grinnell, Charles E., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hofstadter, Richard, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Holt, Henry, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Kasden, S. Samuel, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Keller, Carl T., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Keogh, Andrew, 1925, 1934-1935, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Kimball, Chase, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Knight, N., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Knopf, ALfred A., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Langdon, William Chauncy, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lawrence, David, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lee, Alfred M., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lowry, E.G., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - MacGraw, Arthur B., 1934, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mendel, L.B., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mendell, Clarence Whittlesey, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Meyer, Eugene, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Millard, William Ekin, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Miller, Burr, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - More, Paul E., 1909-1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Murphy, Fred, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Myers, Walter, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Naman, Wilford W., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Noyes, C. Reinold, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Parker, C.H., undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Parsons, Herbert, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Peltz, W.L.L., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Peter, Julius C., 1921, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Pickering, Fred M., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Posert, Hardwig P., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Pratt, Anne S., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Resor, Stanley, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Robinson, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ryce, L.C., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Shaw, Ralph M., 1933-1935, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sinn, Ephraim E., 1932, 1934, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Smitley, R.L., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Starr, Harris E., 1931, 1936, 1941, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Stewart, John, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Stewart, W. K., 1910, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1910, 1913, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Strelinger, D., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sumner, Eliot, Mrs., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sumner, George S., 1910 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Sumner, Graham, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Swain, George F., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Taussig, F. W., 1916 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Taylor, C. Harold, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tetlow, Henry, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Thurber, C. H., 1927, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tilton, A., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tinkham, George Holden, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Todd, Arthur J., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tompkins, Ethel H., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tuttle, Harold S., undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Tyson, Floyd T., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Vincent, George, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Ward, Henshaw, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Warner, John DeWitt, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Watt, Merrill W., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Whalen, F., 1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Whalen, Robert, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Williamson, Arthur C., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Wood, G. W., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Wright, Henry P., 1909 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Wright, Howell, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Wu, Ching Chao, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - unidentified, 1916-1940, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence not to Keller, 1896-1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Writings by Keller
    - Typed preliminary draft for press notices of a speech entitled "Sumner", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Notes and fragmentary pages of draft of Reminiscences of William Graham Sumner, 1909, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Anthropologic Miscellanea", 1910 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Writings by Others and Unidentified
    - Coudert, Frederic René, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Fifty years of Irish Agriculture," by Thomas Kennedy, 1899 January 17 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Retrenchment in national expenditure," by R. C. Leffingwell, 1921 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - An account of the forty-fifth reunion in June 1924 of the Class of 1879, by Ambrose Tighe, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Peasant emancipation in Denmark," an article from The Nation, 1899 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Concerning economics and U.S. government bonds," an article from C.F. Childs and Company's investment bulletin, 1934 March (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified typescript fragment of an essay on evolution, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Report of a trip to Washington, D.C., August 14-16, 1905, in the interests of a commercial museum at Yale University," by A. Longley Bishop (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - William Graham Sumner Club
    - Correspondence, publications, and notes, 1935, 1940, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - William Graham Sumner's anniversaries: press releases, telegram, 1935, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Financial Records
    - Receipt of payment, 1910 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Additional material, Accession 2002-M-057
  This addition is arranged in five series: correspondence; writings; William Graham Sumner Club; financial records; and personal and family.
  - Correspondence, 1898-1956; Series I
    The series is arranged alphabetically by last name of correspondent.
    - A, 1916-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B, 1931-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Blumer, George, 1941-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
    - Brady, Tom P., 1928-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - C (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Chisolm, Ralph W., 1944-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Coe, Ralph H., 1943-1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Commercial and Industrial Geography, 1926-1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - D, 1915-1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - E (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - F (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - G, 1910-1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - H, 1916-1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Harrity, Lowery & Thompson, 1898-1902, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Hinks, Carroll C., 1954, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - I, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - J, 1915-1956 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Junkers, Selma, 1931-1951, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - K, 1901-1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Keller, Carl, 1931-1954 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Keller, Caroline [Mrs. A. G., wife], 1918-1952, undated (Box 3, Folder 22 - 23)
    - Keller, Caroline [daughter], 1932-1956, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Keller, Deane [son], 1921-1956, undated (Box 3, Folder 25 - 27)
    - Keller, Elsa [daughter], 1930-1953, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Keller, Katherine, 1944-1952, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - L, 1927-1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - M (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - N, 1930-1951, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Norland, Mutter, 1930-1955, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - O, 1942-1956 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - P, 1911-1956 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - R, 1926-1956 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Russell, Fletcher A., 1949-1952, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - S, 0 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Science of Society, 1927-1953, undated (Box 4, Folder 39 - 40)
    - Smitley, Robert L., 1946-1956 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - T, 1916-1956, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - U, 1946-1954, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - V, 1915-1956 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - W, 1909-1951, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Wilkie, Wendell W. [petition concerning presidential campaign and supporting materials] (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Y, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Unidentified, 1905-1956, undated (Box 5, Folder 48 - 49)
  - Writings, 1893-1941; Series II
    This series is composed of short writings and class lecture notes. The short writings are arranged alphabetically by title. Untitled short writings follow the works with titles and are organized alphabetically by subject content. The class lecture notes are arranged alphabetically by the name of the course.
    - Short writings [articles, bibliographies, dramas, essays, lectures, letters to the editor, poetry, reports and speeches]
      - "The ABC of Social Science", 1920 (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - "Alcetis" [poetry], undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - "The Army as a School", undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - "The B. A. Degree in America", 1917 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - Bibliography of Keller's writing, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 54)
      - "Books as Tools", 1903 (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - "The Central Issue of the Conference", undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
      - "Comments on my Manuscript", undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - "Conception of Political Science on Evolutionary Lines", undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
      - "Courtesy & Reason as Political Assets?", undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
      - "Economic Organization in its Lowest Terms", undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
      - "Elevating a Profession", undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
      - "Enervating Fatalism", 1927 (Box 6, Folder 62)
      - "Evidence", 1939 (Box 6, Folder 63)
      - "Forward", 1916 (Box 6, Folder 64)
      - "Have We a New World After the War?, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
      - "How History Looks to the Evolutionist", 1921 (Box 6, Folder 66)
      - "Human Brotherhood", undated (Box 6, Folder 67)
      - "The Ithakans", undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
      - Letter to the editor, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 69)
      - "The Limits of Eugenics", 1912 (Box 6, Folder 70)
      - Los Conquistadors de Bogotá, undated (Box 6, Folder 71)
      - "The Medicine Man", undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
      - "The Modern Mode of Colonization", undated (Box 6, Folder 73)
      - National War Work Council Lectures, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 74)
      - "New-comers Among the Sciences", undated (Box 6, Folder 75)
      - "On Getting Ready to do Things", undated (Box 6, Folder 76)
      - "On Keeping the Hand to the Plow", undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
      - "On Taking Out a National Insurance Policy", 1917 (Box 6, Folder 78)
      - Poems, 1893-1894, undated (Box 6, Folder 79)
      - "The Post-War College", undated (Box 6, Folder 80)
      - "Postwar Education", undated (Box 6, Folder 81)
      - "Professional Renumeration", undated (Box 6, Folder 82)
      - "Professor Sumner and Laissez Faire", undated (Box 6, Folder 83)
      - "Queries on Ethnography for Students", 1903 (Box 6, Folder 84)
      - "Race Distinction", 1925 (Box 6, Folder 85)
      - "Reflections on Current Topics", undated (Box 6, Folder 86)
      - "Report to the Commissioner of Education", undated (Box 7, Folder 87)
      - "Review Over Matter", undated (Box 7, Folder 88)
      - Reviews of "The Science of Society", 1927-1928, undated (Box 7, Folder 89)
      - "The Science of Society", undated (Box 7, Folder 90)
      - "The Social Sciences", 1922 (Box 7, Folder 91)
      - "Societal Evolution", 1922 (Box 7, Folder 92)
      - "Sociology", 1922 (Box 7, Folder 93)
      - "Summer" [eulogy for Summer], 1910 (Box 7, Folder 94)
      - "The Taming of Fire", 1910 (Box 7, Folder 95)
      - "What Becomes Now of Colonization?, undated (Box 7, Folder 96)
      - "Why Study History", 1917 (Box 7, Folder 97)
      - "The Yellow Peril?", undated (Box 7, Folder 98)
      - Untitled
        - College teaching [speech], undated (Box 7, Folder 99)
        - Conflict in Venezuela, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 100)
        - Crisis and normality, undated (Box 7, Folder 101)
        - Education, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 102)
        - Evolution, 1909, 1938, n.d (Box 7, Folder 103 - 104)
        - Introduction to the Study of Sociology [review], 1916 (Box 7, Folder 105)
        - Invention and colonization, undated (Box 7, Folder 106)
        - Man's relation to nature, undated (Box 7, Folder 107)
        - Military morale, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 108)
        - Moral branch of army, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 109)
        - Mussolini [transcript], undated (Box 7, Folder 110)
        - Russian novel, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 111)
        - Social sciences, undated (Box 7, Folder 112)
        - Sociology, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 113)
        - Sociology as a science, undated (Box 7, Folder 114)
        - Sumner project [reports on], 1916-1924 (Box 7, Folder 115)
        - World War II, undated (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Class lecture notes
      - "Anthropology", undated (Box 8, Folder 117)
      - "Introduction to Social Sciences", undated (Box 8, Folder 118)
      - "The Science of Society", undated (Box 8, Folder 119 - 120)
      - _ (Box 9, Folder 121 - 124)
      - Unidentified
        - 1916-1941 (Box 10, Folder 125)
        - no date (Box 10, Folder 126 - 127)
  - William Graham Sumner Club, 1943-1949; Series III
    This series is composed of correspondence, membership lists and publications of the William Graham Sumner Club. The correspondence is organized chronologically.
    - Correspondence [chronological]
      - 1943 (Box 11, Folder 128)
      - 1944
        - Jan - Jun (Box 11, Folder 129)
        - Jul - Dec (Box 11, Folder 130)
      - 1945-1949 (Box 11, Folder 131)
      - no date (Box 11, Folder 132)
    - Membership lists, 1943-1949, undated (Box 11, Folder 133)
    - Publications, 1943-1947 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Financial Records, 1892-1952; Series IV
    The series is comprised of account books; copyrights and contracts; and correspondence, all of which are arranged chronologically.
    - Account books
      - Household (Box 12, Folder 135 - 136)
      - Miscellaneous, 1892-1952, undated (Box 12, Folder 137)
    - Copyrights and contracts (Box 13, Folder 138 - 140)
    - Correspondence and other records, 1944-1953, undated (Box 13, Folder 141)
  - Personal and Family, 1857-1956; Series V
    Materials in this series consist of a variety of personal and family memorabilia that are arranged by person. Items about or belonging to Albert Galloway Keller, Caroline Keller, and their children appear first. Materials about or belonging to Keller's relatives and William Sumner Graham follow.
    - Albert Galloway Keller, Caroline Keller, and children
      - Address books, 1903, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 142)
      - Class notebooks, 1893-1904 (Box 14, Folder 143)
      - Condolences, 1956, undated (Box 14, Folder 144 - 146)
      - Course books, 1901-1908, undated (Box 14, Folder 147)
      - Diplomas, 1892-1899
        See: Box 20
      - Engraved brass plates, undated (Box 15, Folder 148)
      - Hillhouse High School memorabilia, 1892-1917 (Box 15, Folder 149)
      - Legal documents
        - Marriage certificate, 1898 (Box 15, Folder 150)
        - Military documents [appointments, discharge], 1917-1919 (Box 15, Folder 151)
        - Passport [with supporting documentation], 1926-1929, undated (Box 15, Folder 152)
        - Wills, codicils and materials concerning the estate of Albert Galloway Keller, 1912-1956, undated (Box 15, Folder 153)
        - Will, codicils and materials concerning the estate of Caroline Keller [wife], 1952 (Box 15, Folder 154)
      - Maps, undated (Box 15, Folder 155)
      - Newspaper clippings [research topics], 1903-1956, undated (Box 15, Folder 156 - 159)
      - Notebooks
        - Anatomical drawings, undated (Box 16, Folder 160)
        - Literary diary, 1892-1896 (Box 16, Folder 161)
      - Obituaries of Albert Galloway Keller, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 162)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 16, Folder 163)
      - Report cards, undated (Box 16, Folder 164)
      - Scrapbook [unidentified], undated (Box 16, Folder 165)
      - Yale University
        - Class album, 1896
          See: Box 21
        - Memorabilia
          - 1898 (Box 16, Folder 166)
          - 1903-1942 (Box 17, Folder 167)
          - 1943-1946 (Box 17, Folder 168)
          - no date [reunion photographs] (Box 17, Folder 169)
    - Relatives
      - Gussman, Emma J. [Keller's mother-in-law; release and indemnification of estate], 1951 (Box 17, Folder 170)
      - Keller, Jeremiah [Keller's father; letterbook], 1884-1887 (Box 17, Folder 171)
      - Smith Family [Keller's mother's family]
        - Family Bible and notebook, 1880, undated (Box 17, Folder 172)
        - Insurance policy for John Smith [Keller's grandfather], 1869 (Box 17, Folder 173)
        - Memory album belonging to Laura S. Smith [Keller's mother], 1857-1867 (Box 17, Folder 174)
        - Papers belonging to Laura and Mary Smith [Keller's mother and aunt], 1858-1860, undated (Box 17, Folder 175)
        - Photograph albums belonging to Laura S. and Hattie Smith [Keller's mother and aunt], undated (Box 18, Folder 176)
        - Photographs [daguerreotypes], undated (Box 18, Folder 177)
    - Sumner, William Graham
      - Grade books, publication, and book, 1895-1954 (Box 18, Folder 178)
      - Leather pouch, undated (Box 18, Folder 179)
    - Unidentified note cards, undated (Box 19)
  - Oversize
    - Diplomas, 1892-1899 (Box 20)
    - Yale University class album, 1896 (Box 21)